# Julie Marie Evans

713-447-0724 <u>JULIEMEVANS17@GMAIL.COM</u> KILGORE, TX <u>LINKEDIN</u> | <u>GITHUB</u> | <u>BLOG</u> | <u>PORTFOLIO WEBSITE</u>

#### PROFILE

Experienced in React, JavaScript, and Ruby on Rails based programming with a background in problem-solving. Possess strong skills in organization and project management that encompasses self-motivation and seeing ideas through to completion. Enthusiastic towards design which helps with styling projects. Great understanding of Linguistics that provides a basis in language learning, including programming languages.

#### TECHNICAL SKILLS

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, Next JS, TypeScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Tailwind CSS, SCSS, Ruby, Ruby on Rails, JSON, SQL, PostgreSQL, SQLite, and Redux.

#### SECURITY CLEARANCE

CONFIDENTIAL-LEVEL CLEARANCE - MAY.2023-PRESENT

#### **EXPERIENCE**

### WEB DEVELOPER, PINGWIND; CDC CONTRACT MAY.2023-OCT.2024

- Implemented "Clean Slate" to reduce excessive files and transition to updated sites with new look and feel.
- Created new BMI Calculators and updated the Alcohol Quiz refreshing the UI, adding features, and improving the functionality.
- Collaborated with team members to run security scans and remediate PDFs to be 508 compliant.

# SOFTWARE ENGINEER, CHINGU JAN.2023-FEB.2023

- Worked as part of a team of 5 engineers to build an e-commerce web application, using React.
- Used a combination of Figma and GitHub to plan, organize, and coordinate the process with my team.

# FREELANCE TRANSLATOR, NAQADA STUDIO MAY.2021

- Translated 10 episodes of an anime TV show from Japanese into English.
- · Listened to audio from video to aid in translating the Japanese dialogue transcription.

# TRANSLATOR, TED CONFERENCE LLC OCT.2023-DEC.2024

- Watched videos and translated Japanese dialogue transcriptions into English.
- Time-coded the translated dialogue in sync with audio for subtitles.

### **EDUCATION**

### FLATIRON SCHOOL - OCT.2021-SEP.2022

Software Engineering program covering the fundamentals of Full-Stack Web Development.

# UNIVERSITY OF NORTH TEXAS; DENTON, TX - JUN.2016-MAY.2020

Bachelor of Arts degree in Integrative Studies with focus in Anthropology, Linguistics, and International Studies.